Michael Paglione

32 Schultz Road Berlin, CT 06037 (860) 849-3864 pagman777@gmail.com

RETAIL EXPERIENCE

Manchester Mazda, Manchester, CT — Mazda Brand Specialist

May 2021 - January 2022

Set and exceed personal sales goals to drive company sales. Uphold the image of the Mazda brand by providing excellent customer service and vehicle knowledge. Compile the needs of the customer such as style, features, and budget to match them with a vehicle that best suits their requests. Close as many customers as possible by leveraging the Mazda brand and culture of the dealership. Utilize the dealership CRM to actively engage and follow up with self–generated leads in a timely fashion.

Lowes, New Haven, CT — Sales Floor Supervisor, Front End Operations

January 2021 - May 2021

Deliver the Lowe's experience through SMART customer service by being a role model for exemplary customer service and de-escalating customer issues. Drive sales of the internet department by ensuring the team is engaging customers on arrival, actively following up with static orders on a daily basis, and delivering stellar customer service. Utilize LTR 'Likelihood to Recommend' scores to discover opportunities in the business and embrace solutions to drive profitability. Leverage the Head Cashier team to set and achieve goals for their cashiers on LTR, credit applications, and active engagement to increase business ROI.

Lowes, New Haven, CT — Sales Floor Supervisor, Appliances, Cabinets, Millwork

September 2020 - January 2021

Maintain department standards such as cleanliness, downstocking, safety, and inventory management through delegation of tasks. Work closely with the receiving team to coordinate delivery of major appliances and monitor large freight shipments to reduce inventory shrink through mastery of store systems. Deliver the Lowe's experience through SMART customer service by being a role model for de-escalating customer issues and proactively monitoring LTR (likelihood to recommend) scores. Identify and address safety concerns and hazards by teaching associates and conducting safety walks. Coach-to and provide solutions to the team and store for effective time management to improve efficiency, increase sales, and drive LTR scores.

SKILLS

Stellar customer service
Effective problem solver
Detail oriented
Strong interpersonal skills
Self-motivated
5+ years management
experience

10+ years customer service experience

Education

University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT — B.A. Music

August 2006 - May 2011

Lowes, New Haven, CT — Sales Specialist, Flooring

July 2020 - September 2020

Maintain department cleanliness through downstocking and zone recovery. Seek and interact with customers to promote Lowe's brand by offering flooring services using their SMART customer service model. Use store generated and personal leads to close sales on flooring installations. Engage the DIY customer to add additional products and services to their basket to exceed their needs and expectations.

Capital Carpet and Flooring Specialists , Wilmington, MA — Assistant Project Manager

May 2018 - January 2020

Assist the project manager by completing task work such as meeting strict deadlines, corresponding with general contractors and sales representatives. Recording and organizing data such as purchase orders, values schedules, quotes, and billing information. Developed and cultivated relationships with general contractors and sales representatives to promote the culture of the company through its services.

Starbucks Coffee Company, Old Saybrook, CT — Store Manager

July 2013 - May 2018

Responsible for overall store operations such as: hiring, scheduling, inventory management, performance management, problem solving, coaching to improve, teambuilding, and multitasking. Leveraged multiple store reports to forecast and exceed sales volume goals by motivating the team through the cultivation of brand behaviors. Extended the brand image through community outreach by donating to local events and working closely with the town Chamber of Commerce. Major achievements included sales growth year over year, above 50% controllable contribution, and 8% yearly hourly turnover.

Michael Paglione

32 Schultz Road Berlin, CT 06037 (860) 849-3864 quirkyclarinet@gmail.com

PERFORMANCE EXPERIENCE

Goodspeed Opera House, East Haddam, CT — Reed 2 Substitute

September 2016 - Current

Changes in Latitudes - Premiere Jimmy Buffett Tribute, New England — Woodwinds

July 2017 - Current

The World Famous Glenn Miller Orchestra, USA, Canada, Japan — Alto 2/Clarinet/Flute

February 2019 - December 2019

Freelance Woodwind Doubler, CT — Woodwinds

January 2008 - Current

Playing woodwinds in High Schools, regional and community theaters all over Connecticut. Chairing or sub for the following books:

A Chorus Line** Addams Family All Shook Up Annie

1776

Assassins Big River Bye Bye Birdie Cabaret** Candide

Cats Chasing Rainbows Chicago** City of Angels

Company Connecticut Christmas Carol

Footloose* Grease* Guys and Dolls** Hairspray

Hunchback of Notre Dame*

In the Heights* Into the Woods Iolanthe

Jesus Christ Superstar Kiss Me Kate** Les Miserables**

Little Shop of Horrors**

Man of La Mancha** Mary Poppins**

Midlife! The Crisis Musical My Fair Lady

Oklahoma** On the Town Saturday Night Fever Seuessical* Shrek the Musical Sister Act Smokev Joe's Cafe

The 25th Annual Putnam County Spelling Bee*

The Drowsy Chaperone**

The Music Man

The Mystery of Edwin Drood** The Princess and the Pea The Rocky Horror Picture Show* The Sound of Music

The Wiz

Thoroughly Modern Millie*

Two Gentleman of Verona

Urinetown* West Side Story Wonderful Town You Are Here

*denotes multiple theaters

**denotes playing different books at different theaters

Education

University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT B.A. Music

August 2006 - May 2011

Teaching Experience

The Rectory School

October 2010 - February 2019

Private instruction in Clarinet with occasional vearly students for flute, saxophone, and oboe

The Killingly School of Music

Fall 2011 - Spring 2013

Private instruction on saxophone, clarinet, and flute.

East Lyme High School **Marching Band**

Fall 2012 - Winter 2013

Woodwind and Marching

Putnam High School Marching band

Fall 2014 - Winter 2014

Assistant music director.